at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age do we learn to have better
conversations with ourselves
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]
foreign
I'm really honored to uh to get the
invites here I was listening to your
show love it awesome
I I appreciate your uh authenticity your
curiosity and
and there's a great Vibe coming from
through your voice when you're speaking
I feel uh you know
comforted I feel like we've known each
other for a while so I'm excited to see
where this conversation goes man thank
you so much yeah I'm really happy to
have YouTube right I've um I've been
consuming your content for some time so
it's cool too I've actually thought
about messaging you for quite some time
to get you on here um
but is it the scheduling for my podcast
is a little wonky and my schedule is a
bit inconsistent so um the last thing I
would want to do is have to like
reschedule because I get a gig that
really needs me or something so
um yeah man I'm I'm pretty pumped to
talk to you too I I was just listening
to your stuff this morning again and I I
kind of had that same thing like it kind
of
um I know it's a little dorky but it
feels like we've known each other or
something like there's just some relay
uh relatability to the things that you
talk about and I think
there's something to be said about
um you know there's there's an innate
loneliness that comes with the Kundalini
Awakening experience because you're like
who do I talk to about this who knows
anything about this so just hearing
someone who's gone through the same
thing you're like oh okay that makes
sense yeah
yeah there's definitely a major
overarching theme of being alone and uh
confused and
and wondering what the hell's going on
with you for sure for sure yeah and then
um
uh yeah and then trying to explain to
someone you know because people want to
listen to us people you know who love us
are you know they're open eared in every
way they're like I want to help you what
are you going this seems like you're
going through something but then you try
to explain you know a way that you put
it before was a snake coming out of your
butt uh and that that made me laugh like
trying to explain to someone yeah well
there's a serpent going up my spine and
I'm just stressed about it and you know
so it's yeah it's pretty tough
well um cool man uh so like I said it's
it's pretty casual on my end um I like
to be able to have space for both of us
to kind of ramble on
um and uh you know stumble upon the
questions that that are natural
um but I would love to start with kind
of your bio your background who are you
um how did you get into Kundalini
Awakening and then we can kind of go
what is Kundalini Awakening after that
and we'll we'll let it rip after that so
I would love to know Brent who are you
what is it that you do
well I go by Brent spirits of course
that's uh
an alias my first name is Brent uh
Spirit came about
uh just with the it was just a branding
issue I work as a photographer under my
you know my given name and when I began
doing this spiritual work
maybe you've experienced it yourself
Jacob I know you're involved in a few
things branding is a whole uh it's a
whole challenge you know how do you
present yourself so I was doing
photography
and of course I'm interested in uh you
know Kundalini Awakening Spiritual
Awakening some kind of weird stuff and
initially I started
uh you know just as
my my given name with these two
different very very conflicting uh
uh Explorations and people are getting a
little freaked out and stuff so I had to
separate my Brands and so I came up with
Brent's spirit I just to denote the uh
you know the spiritual aspect so I go by
brand Spirits
um and I like to say that I'm a
spiritual teacher
over the past uh 15 years or so I've
undergone a pretty intense Spiritual
Awakening Journey uh involving things
like Kundalini Awakening uh Kundalini
process uh there's some been some
interesting shifts in perception
um some ups and downs overall that we'll
get into but
in short uh after some of the the shifts
that I I went through I began writing
online uh back in the in the days of
Tumblr I was uh just writing online
about some of my experiences as a way to
process things
um
and people began to say Hey you know
similar things have happened to me
I'm really stuck here I'm challenged
with this do you have some information
you have some insights and advice some
guidance
maybe even a resource and so I ended up
you know responding to some of these
questions and then the questions became
coming you know more and more frequently
and suddenly I found myself playing the
role of spiritual teacher so that's how
I found myself in this role but um
we can uh backtrack a little bit and
explore a little bit of how this all
began for me
so I've told my story in a few different
places already so I'll try and come at
it from a different angle maybe uh
there's some things that uh we can
discuss a little more I know in some of
your episodes you were talking about
things like dissociation
um you know this this kind of being out
of your body you know being disembodied
this type of thing and so
and reflecting on uh you know how our
conversation might go I thought maybe
maybe I could start talking a little bit
about my experience of dissociation so
as a young kid
I felt very free in the sense that I
didn't feel that I was this body or I
was the mind I don't even think I had a
formulated an ego per se
um this identity of like Brent the
little boy I don't think there was Brent
the little boy there was just life
and I was experiencing life
and there wasn't a clear distinction
between I'm here and the world is out
there there wasn't like a separation it
was just life happening of course I
couldn't articulate any of this back
then Looking Back Now I can put some
words to it but still I don't think it
really captures it but
it was basically a sort of meditative
state
free from the attachment identification
with the body
and from that freedom also came
uh
uh the space
to I guess what we would call dissociate
so as I became to get older I would go
through different experiences that would
now begin to form this identity of Brent
I began to feel that I was my body and
the world was out there and maybe there
were threats in the world and so I had
to protect this body I had to protect
this ego this mind uh who could be
threatened
um challenged offended or traumatized
um you know labeled all these sorts of
things so then this ego began to form
identification with the body began to
form
but I found myself at times when I was
going through something traumatic
maybe even that was if I was just
getting you know lectured by my parents
uh because I had done something wrong
I found myself dissociating
and leaving my body and it felt like a
protective mechanism a survival
mechanism to uh avoid the intense
situation so I find myself leaving my
body but from there it was it wasn't
like when I was a younger kid it was now
a little bit uncomfortable and scary and
I remember you know maybe somebody was
threatening me
um or scolding me
or you know one time I remember I had
done something wrong the teacher took me
outside the classroom I was talking to
me in the hallway and I remember leaving
my body she became like very tiny in my
perception like a little tiny little
person just her head was just you know
scolding me and I was just just
listening to this talking happening but
you know completely out of my body
in a place where I felt safe
um and so there's a there was like this
blending of this meditative state
it's dissociative state
um using it
initially it was Freedom now it was more
of like escaping to survive so there's
like these uh these themes are emerging
um
eventually in high school I found myself
um really depressed I'd gone through
some heartbreak you know the ups and
downs of high school and I I don't think
that um it's unusual I think we all go
through some sort of
uh chaos in high school but for whatever
reason I was really sensitive and fell
into a really deep depression at the
time I didn't know it was depression I
didn't know what Depression was I didn't
know what anxiety was I just felt I'm
sad and of course I'm sad life sucks
um so you know it didn't seem like a
mental health issue I don't think mental
health was even a conversation back then
about 15 years ago it was I I imagine
you two had you know very little mental
health awareness back then
yeah go ahead yeah yeah okay yeah yeah
so so it was just I just felt alone sad
I didn't know you know who do I talk to
you know it was just like this
experience I was having but I found that
instead of being able to now dissociate
that was like
stuck in my body like suffocating in
this body in the mind I couldn't find
any reprieve any release any
spaciousness it was me it was I was
completely identified with these
feelings
completely identified with the minds I
was a victim to the world that you know
had victimized me that was out there
separate from me and that meditative
State I had as a child even the ability
to kind of dissociate was completely
unavailable to me
um and so I felt like I was quite
literally suffocating in my body
um eventually I found ideas of
meditation and mindfulness that
laid a bit of a road map and pointed me
towards
getting a bit of spaciousness again so
if you're familiar with Eckhart Tolle
he's got the book The Power of Now
he explains about how we could come
identified with the thoughts we think
that we are the thought stream
the pain in the body we become
identified with it and you know they
fuel each other the more emotional
negativity you feel in your body it
fuels more negative thoughts which fuels
more negative emotions and there's
momentum
but what he said was you could take a
step back and you can witness this
unfolding you could witness the thoughts
you could witness the emotions in your
body and from witnessing you're able to
take a step back and then you can allow
that momentum to uh
to play itself out and uh you know wind
down
and so I found this and I
you know it felt so familiar to me to be
able to witness and take a step back and
just observe
felt so familiar and then in these the
Eckhart Tolle's work he says you know
this is stuff that you've always known
this is nothing new here that I'm
showing you it's what we've always known
you're just remembering and that's
really what it felt like and quite
literally I could think you know this is
what I felt like as a child
and so it validated what I was
experiencing and so I said okay you know
I have to just continue this practice of
being a witness of observing and taking
space and so I began to find ideas from
the East yoga meditation Buddhism
mindfulness
and I thought initially interesting I
thought it was Eckhart Tolle who came up
with all of this stuff himself oh man
this guy's a genius
and so when I found ideas from Buddhism
and Hinduism and yoga I thought oh wait
this guy he didn't come up with this by
himself he's put it into words that I
can understand you know he stripped it
out of the the religious and cultural
context so that I can digest it and then
still that's a feat an incredible
accomplishment
still so grateful for him
and so uh at some point I thought you
know I'll try this thing called
meditation so before this I was if I can
clarify here I was practicing witnessing
just throughout my day like I would just
sit and become like a field of awareness
and look around and maybe it was during
work or play but I didn't sit to
meditate so I thought you know let me
try this thing you know to sit in
meditation and and turn inwards and see
what that's all about
and still my intention was to overcome
depression and anxiety
it wasn't about Enlightenment or
self-realization or anything like that
it was just finding peace
so I remember being in my basement
actually um
as I sat down in meditation and suddenly
like it instantly my my neck began to
Arch and my my chin became to my chest
and then it started to go backwards and
and uh you know this is really strange
it's happening spontaneously I can't
stop it I don't know why this is doing
this
and I felt almost like
like something was coming alive in me
that was controlling my body in this way
I opened my eyes I don't know what that
was about
um
I'm just gonna not do that anymore I
left it at that
I said I'm happy with the mindfulness
approaches as you know being out and
about during my day remembering to come
into the present moment to be a witness
I like those practices the record for me
I don't know what the heck that's that's
scary experience was about I let it be
didn't make much of it after that didn't
talk to anybody about it
um left it at that now
I mean I could pause there
um
have you experienced something similar
in terms of meditation you know these
spontaneous movements and that sort of
thing oh man yeah there's yeah there's
there's so many things that I resonate
with um in so many different directions
that I can take it uh I mean firstly
thank you for being vulnerable and like
opening up about
um you know how you came through this uh
through anxiety and depression and not
so much like you know you read the word
Kundalini in a book and you're like I
want to try that you know I I think
that's kind of a a big point for a lot
of us as we stumble into it or it's um
you know Kundalini almost happens to you
or you think uh what is to you and then
your your catapulted on this whole
spiritual journey of learning like well
what do I mean to me what is me who am
me you know this whole thing um so yeah
I totally had uh very very similar
um the spontaneous I think I've heard
you talk about it in other podcasts as
well is the spontaneous like stretching
and yoga and breath work and meditation
like you just couldn't not meditate like
you just you start to become
um obsessed with it like what like you
you can't go about your everyday life
you know joking about
um you know TV commercial ads and stuff
with everybody when you're just thinking
about being miles away from this meta
perspective of who am I and what is this
and uh
you know yeah yeah once you're
I think it was the same thing for me so
it's funny because it's it's both
terrifying but also so interesting right
so you you learn about this this thing
you have this disassociative state and
uh you recognize because your body is
filled with fear and uh you recognize it
as kind of a defense mechanism in some
ways but then it's also like we were
talking about the beginning it's this
weird remembering you know it's like
when you're reading akhart Tolle's book
uh he's speaking to something where
you're like I already know this in a
weird way he's almost just repainting a
picture kind of like uncovering a
picture that you think you've seen
before you know um and I do think that
it's often locked behind you know a lot
of our our modern world is kind of um
this information is hid behind spiritual
text or religious books or things and
that kind of turns a lot of us off we're
like I don't know about that or we only
have one version of it and it doesn't
include the whole thing
um so yeah in any sort of opening to
explain I think that once we start to
learn about this stuff if we've had a
Kundalini Awakening or any sort of
Awakening experience there is
um uh we just feel heard like our real
self feels heard and seen in in a sense
you know I I I think that uh you're far
from alone in Eckhart Tolle being one of
your you know first spiritual teachers
on the path I know people personally as
well as there's a spiritual teacher um
have you heard of Aaron abke on YouTube
yeah I have yeah so so he was a um an
Evangelical pastor's kid and he had a
lot of similar stuff he had a Kundalini
Awakening but um one of his first kind
of profound he had a few weeks of
samadhi and it was caused by him on his
break he's working at Google as a
personal trainer and uh he was on his
break at work listening to Eckhart Tolle
audiobook and uh he said it kind of like
set him into this state for for multiple
weeks of just like you know kind of what
we would consider an enlightened State
and then he describes how you know he
had things in his personal you know
grounded life that happened and kind of
let him out of it but um
yeah okay
um
I'm trying to think of where we could
take it
um so you had this you had this
experience and then so you're taking
some time to learn about it to read
about it trying to understand what
happened to me
um it sounds like you becoming um kind
of kind of teaching people was sort of a
natural thing so
how does this equate with your
upbringing of what you knew of
spirituality and um I think you were did
you say you were raised in Catholicism
have I heard that okay so what what were
the things that kind of stayed from what
you knew back then um and what were the
things that you kind of had to relearn I
mean so so like this different belief
system how was it different than what
you had learned when you were when you
were a child
well it took it took me a long time to
uh to make sense of some of the uh
more Western religions
um Catholicism in particular
and I'm still learning it and making
more and more sense about it but in
short I was raised to believe that God
was up in the sky
and that we were the poor lowly Sinners
on Earth separate and we had to earn our
way to connecting with God in heaven
when we died
um and by default we were shameful
unworthy Sinners you know original sin
and that sort of thing and so when I
began to understand you know
I I recognize well there are people like
Eckhart Tolle
who are living in a very heightened
state of consciousness
and they haven't died they're still here
so I thought
you know to hell with this Western idea
of God being up in the sky I let it all
go I became uh rather
um
resentful of it for the shame the guilt
the lies
um the uh the mass manipulation that I
was seeing you know the uh
the the industry of organized religion
but but
coming back uh around I I came to see
that
at least in my you know it's a general
statement here but it seems that all of
these organized religions were formed
around a Mystic
who had recognized that God wasn't up in
the sky that God was Within
and they began to you know share a
message of that and that message became
watered down and used to you know
control fear or manipulation and whatnot
and so if we look at uh you know
Christianity Jesus was a Mystic it was a
Mystic that had engaged in you know
rigorous spiritual practice and devotion
and recognized that he was the son of
God in other words he was in a state of
Union with God which is what yoga is
Yoga means Union with God we look at
Buddhism the same thing he recognized
Enlightenment it's different ways and
different ways of looking at it but in
the sense the Buddha was also a Mystic
and so I said well instead of worshiping
these people I can do my best to try and
move towards what they had realized like
a cartolli and then I began to find that
there were people all over the world
that were living in these you know
mystical States teaching about it and so
that's you know snapped me out of this
idea that
um you know God was separate up in the
sky instead I said okay you know I'm not
going to focus on religion I'm going to
focus on spirituality and I think it was
Deepak Chopra who said religion is about
someone else's experience spirituality
is about your experience and that's
where my attention went it went to uh it
being about my experience and so
I
after that experience of meditation I
like I said I didn't make much of it
that the sort of energetic experience
with my spine moving I didn't make much
of it I didn't really know what that was
it wasn't really notable to me
um but I just continued practicing
mindfulness throughout my day
um
eventually it moved from trying to
overcome depression because I think I
had gotten a lot of I made a lot of
progress on those fronts then it became
just I said well I can continue these
practices and move towards
something like Enlightenment or
mysticism or yoga Union with the Divine
and and so I continued on those with
those practices but for a long time
there was no energetic component after
that it was solely
um
to do with with these with with abiding
as mindful awareness there wasn't very
much of an energetic component that came
like it re-emerged later on in my
journey
hmm how so how did it re-emerge are you
talking about um when you're so like
your Kundalini energy actually did you
have an experience where it kind of shot
through the top of your head did you
experience that
okay cool yeah will you explain how that
happened and what that was like for you
mine was a bit different I never had um
the shooting experience from the base of
my spine to the top of my head I had
similar experiences with other um what I
would consider like chakra points
um but but but first how was it for you
what was it like for you yeah so so just
for uh for your audience out there maybe
wondering you know part of my work here
is to dispel the notion that Kundalini
Awakening must require a huge energetic
rising of the spine for many it happens
in in more subtle gradual ways I like to
say that this is the Divine and the
Divine doesn't just move in one
direction from root up to the top of the
head many people also have energetic and
full things that happen downwards some
people have maybe like you said various
chakra points at different different
periods on their path begin to come
activated and whatnot so it looks very
different for for almost anyone and many
people are going through Kundalini
Awakening they don't even know it
because they're saying oh I didn't have
a huge rising up my spine and so I just
want to preface with that because I I in
fact did have a massive rising of my
spine
um of this Kundalini awakens Kundalini
energy so
at age 15 that's when I had this
meditation experience where the spine
started to do that spontaneous movement
it lasted maybe about 30 seconds I came
out of this meditation went around went
along with my day
um it was later on
at I mean three or three years later or
so it's 2012 and at this point I've been
I've been working towards this idea of
self-realization of Enlightenment as a
result of what I learned uh throughout
totally I began to explore more and more
Traditions from the East and I began to
engage in what's called self-inquiry
um inquiring into you know who am I I
was also asking what is true what is
true uh in a very intense way
um because these are right these are
practices that come out of of Zen like
coans
um advaita vedanta
um if maybe some people are familiar
with Ramen and maharshi he had the
practice self-inquiry who am I so I
thought I'll continue these these
practices and just see what happens well
eventually something significant
happened I was I was asking what is true
and suddenly I don't I mean nothing is
true
this is all a rising in Consciousness
like a dream
including myself and if this experience
there was like an energetic opening in
my head
um it felt like my head became so
spacious
and in my head it was completely empty
there was no sense of identity of Brent
the ego the me I
there were thoughts but I recognized
that the thoughts were just there's
initially a void
and a thought would arise
and that thought would pass away back
into the void
and another thought would arise
and I saw it all this is is just
thoughts are Rising one at a time that's
not that's not me
it's quite literally just one thought
arising at a time there's no Center
there that I could say okay yeah this is
me this is I this is Brent this is the
ego this is myself
and so this was interesting
there was a significant shift I knew it
was of a spiritual nature
um and there's an energetic component as
well I I didn't use those terms
initially looking back I see that there
was a significant energetic component
where the the crown chakra or the head
opened up and a lot of Consciousness
flowed inwards into my head
um and so I was abiding in this sort of
uh what some may call a non-dual state
there was no Duality here it was uh it
wasn't Oneness per se but it was just it
was not Tunis
it's a difference there it's very subtle
but there's just not Tunis I knew that
if I'm not if there's no actual entity
called Brent here
well then how can what I take myself to
be be separate from anything else
if for in order for separation to be
here well this idea of Brent would have
to be here to be separate from the world
and so there was this experience of like
well one with everything but with that
similarly to my dissociative States as a
young child
I I was out of my body
my head became so big almost like it had
no no top on it anymore and I was like
almost watch myself like from a third
eye perspective almost like a bird's eye
view
I was just watching the body
and the world and I noticed that
you know it was all like a very spooky
dream that was unfolding on its own
everything was happening automatically
even the processes with my within my own
body because I wasn't in control it was
just happening
and there was
[Music]
um
incredible insights coming here I
recognize that this is what they mean
when the Dao is flowing and everything
is the Dao manifesting and expressing
it's just a flow and I saw the flow so
intensely in this place and so
up until this point I was exploring
teachings from like Zen Buddhism
um neoadvaita which is like a modern
offshoot of invite of adanta which is a
more older uh tradition from the east
from uh from uh The Vedic uh
The Vedic wisdom
and so their philosophies were very much
philosophies
that describe the nature of reality as
being like an illusion as being
consciousness
as being awareness
and so it's very much a philosophical
approach that felt very cerebral
intellectual
um
pretty mind-based
and so I thought well this must be what
they're talking about when they speak
about enlightenments I've recognized
that I don't exist I'm not separate from
anything everything is happening on its
own this is the Dao
I'm not in my body I'm watching my body
and in that place I felt extremely numb
uh no emotional experience practically
whatsoever and I thought well I'm free
from emotions now I'm free from all the
suffering that I was going through all
this time uh it felt okay you know
something is a little weird here and
then I said okay well maybe I'll just
take some time and I'll get used to this
new state then this will be my life now
free from emotions just watch my body
every one with the Dow
and so that's where I
there were some some challenges there I
could talk a little bit about it as well
because
um I did eventually
come across a
a text that describe depersonalization
uh also called dpdr depersonalization
derealization and Zen sickness or
emptiness sickness in which they
describe that some people
uh within Zen for example if they're
meditating a lot they can experience the
Zen sickness where they become
depersonalized and they
feel like everything has become a dream
and I thought oh this is actually what
I'm experiencing Zen sickness something
is not complete here something is a
little off
and so from there I said okay this must
not be the final stage clearly this is a
documented experience
and so
I gotta figure out how to how to cure
myself of Zen sickness
and
I I thought you know I had a Buddhism
teacher in a university course not uh
not a spiritual teacher a professor I
should say professor and so I thought
well maybe they'll have some answers for
me so I approached them and said hey you
know I'm I'm experiencing Zen sickness
and I remember talking to them feeling
completely out of my body
and she said oh you know that's
interesting but honestly I can't help
you I don't know much had she heard
about it at all she I from what I could
tell she hadn't heard about Zen sickness
and she was into practice meditator I
think she had a more of an interest in
the cultural implications of Buddhism
um the ethical uh and cultural
implications and that was her Focus but
when it came to the direct in the
experience of the individual who's
practicing these these uh you know these
spiritual Traditions
um meditation she admitted I I can't
help you I don't practice this could
could I ask you how this made you feel
and this it seems important to ask like
when you opened up to her about this
thing like hey I'm going through this
like
um you know an insane thing that you
you're probably barely able to put words
around and you just assume like she
probably she could probably help me you
know she she knows about this stuff I've
heard her mention Zen before ever you
know whatever and then when she was like
I don't know about it how did that make
you feel did that send you backwards at
all or yeah it was uh it was horrifying
it was quite literally horrifying
because in within Zen sickness within
what I was experiencing I felt like
everything was a dream I felt like
nothing was real nothing was true and so
when I read about Zen's sickness I
thought okay so maybe
maybe I'm not actually alone in this
dream and there are actual people out
there that can help me get back to
feeling real again
and so when I approached her and she
gave me this response I can't help you
Brent it further validated my mindset or
my perspective or what had happened to
me in that
I thought wow I am alone and she is like
a character in my dream
um
that's what a character would say you
know if you're in a dream and you try to
say hey buddy we're dreaming and say no
we're not or even if you said hey can
you help me get out of this dream to say
what do you mean where do you want to go
right they won't they won't have
anything for you right yeah what dream
what do you mean so it was like
okay you know she's saying I can't help
you
um
and I could tell she felt
a little embarrassed because
I mean here she is Professor of Buddhism
unequipped to help me and so out of her
I think her embarrassment I think she
tried to save a little bit of Face by
saying you know I just moved here from
Chicago if we were back in Chicago I
would have maybe recommended uh
you know like a zen teacher but I don't
know anybody here and so I thought okay
you know why don't I figure out where
the closest Zen place is
um and they can help me
uh there's like a Zen Monastery or
something there's got to be something um
I was in Toronto
and so I found a Zen Center
and I thought okay I'll make my way over
there so it was a long bus ride I
remember being on the bus looking around
at everyone's face and just thinking you
know they have no idea what I'm going
through
like they have no idea what just
happened to my mind my mind was quite
literally blown apart
my entire perception of the world has
been shattered and these people are just
you know going about their day and I
remember sitting there as a very
interesting contrast
eventually I found myself to the Zen
Center and I I walk up to the door
and knock on the door it's like this old
sort of a state house type of type thing
Matt opens a door and I say hey look man
I think I'm going through Zen sickness I
need help
I I don't know what's wrong
um and I but I know that something is
wrong
um
and he says oh you know the teacher's
not here
and uh to be honest they don't really
help people off the street
and I thought oh my God you know
another uh you know dead end
um
and he says you know give me a second
and he comes back he gives me a paper
and it's like a mental health crisis
hotline so let's call these people
they'll help you
and I remember looking at this and
thinking man
this is spiritual
this is a spiritual crisis or emergency
that I'm going through I don't think I
had those words yet but I knew that this
wasn't
solely mental illness this was spiritual
in nature
because it coincided so closely with
what I had read as descriptions of these
Awakenings and experiences of Satori and
ego death and no self
it was consistent with those experiences
and so I knew if I call these people
they may not
they may be even less equipped than my
Buddhist teacher or less equipped than
even this guy who was maybe practicing
Zen I don't know if he was a teacher or
not but
even he couldn't even give me any word
of advice I don't know what somebody on
a mental health crisis is going to say
to me when I say hey I feel like you
know I'm a dream my mind has been
blasted open I don't have an ego or I've
seen through my ego now what are they
supposed to say to me right and so I
thought this is spiritual in nature and
I took stock I said well somehow
I came across that term Zen sickness
something
is orchestrating this unfolding and I
tuned in and I felt the Dao the flow of
the Dao the flow of life and I said that
is taking care of me it's directing me
further on my journey I just need to
acknowledge that I haven't yet landed
and arrived a significant shift has
taken place
but I need to keep going and following
whatever is supported me this thus far
because I thought it was a great gift to
even have come to realize it wasn't
sickness was
um I forgot to mention it but
in my University course the Buddhism
course I didn't do any of the readings I
was so busy with trying to become
enlightened but for some reason during
this Zen sickness experience in my head
was blasted open at some point I just
grabbed the book The Textbook opened it
to a random page and there was Zen
sickness emptiness sickness and there
was a description and that's when I
recognized what was going on and so I
thought well something inspired me to
open the book clearly that was the flow
the Dao this is my intuition something
in some intelligence is orchestrating my
unfolding I can trust that intelligence
I can surrender it was not easy I was
like what else do I got I mean people
can't help me I went to the Zen Center
they can't help me what am I supposed to
do but trust and so I put all my faith
in this intelligence that was you know
that seemed to be holding me and coaxing
me to keep going and with that surrender
I had to let go of this belief that you
know I had I'd reached full
enlightenments and uh be humble enough
to continue forward on the journey
wow okay wow that's so incredible I mean
I think uh I think many would probably
uh relate to you know you picking up
this book and you turn to the page and
suddenly is kind of speaking about what
you're talking about I have uh I've had
conversations on the podcast and with
friends
um who have had the experience of going
to the library and like a book fell off
the shelf and that's the book that they
needed to buy or or check out you know
so interesting um wow I mean yeah so I
felt it important to ask how you felt in
that moment
um when you kind of like okay there's a
clear this thing going on with me
someone's gonna help me I'm gonna go to
them and I'm gonna tell them what's
going on and she's like man I don't know
you know I I I haven't experienced that
I don't know
um because for my journey it was also I
think that I had a lot of the similar
thing of
I would have moments where I'm kind of
explaining these things to people or I'm
talking about them and I'm rambling on
about I'm having this and I'm having
depersonalization I'm using these words
that not only they don't know but then I
kind of like Get present with the moment
and with this person you know whether
it's been like a friend or just someone
I've met
um and I realize they don't know what
the heck I'm talking about and then it's
like this oh no yeah you really are
alone you know that snapping out a
reminder that you know this is a in a
sense a dream world you know and it's
not to um uh you know negate the the
teachers or or friends who are there
like they just simply don't know they
love us and they want us to feel okay
too but
um they don't know what you're talking
about like if you haven't experienced it
to like hear these things it's just so
far removed from our everyday Waking
Life that it's very difficult to
understand you know
um so yeah I I think um
so okay so so how would you say that
yeah I mean it seems like you kind of
fell back on your path of okay I have to
find the answers for what this is like I
have to find what's true to me so you're
going through this you have what you
would consider Zen sickness you're
having a Kundalini Awakening um I'm not
sure if at this time if you knew that if
you would consider it that or you have
that terminology no
um so so how did you begin to
stabilize yourself after all of this you
know what what started making things
more normal because what what I noticed
something that's wonderful to point out
is it's not like you just tried to
forget about all of it and tried to go
back to your everyday you know nine to
five sort of picket fenced life
um you were able to integrate this you
were able to keep this wonderful
information but also become more
grounded you know and I'm sure that your
everyday Waking Life talking with people
who are unawakened is is a completely
normal part of your experience now you
know it's because I think that when
we're going through these things we're
like I don't know if I'm ever going to
be able to talk to a normal person again
I don't know if I'm ever going to be
able to like I can't go back to a job
you know this is this is so far-fetched
but I mean it seems that it seems that
you have integrated these things and
stabilized yourself so what was the next
step on your journey Brent of
um
um I guess integrating all of this
because it seems like you've done so
well you know it seems like now you're
able to take the things you've
experienced and you know you're a
spiritual teacher now and you're helping
a lot of people who stumble across your
video so I mean what was that jump like
how did you get to where kind of where
you are now so to say
yeah great well well thank you thank you
yeah so it's it's been a very long
journey so this initial experience took
place in 2012. so it's been about 10
years of integrating that experience as
well as others that so you know we can
get into as well but that experience
um going back to when we were talking
about Kundalini Awakening
and how it can move in different
directions it can be subtle it can be
intense it can look very different I
would describe this as a top-down
Awakening so there's the idea of the
energy rising from the root upwards but
then some people can have this like
top-down experience where the crown is
what initially has that impor of energy
and I could bring about a lot of
um interesting shifts and perception uh
shifts in the way that we we view our
own ego and that sort of thing that I've
been describing thus far so it was a
top-down awaking that I was experiencing
now I didn't know that it was a top-down
experience I thought that was the whole
thing because like I said the Traditions
that I was exploring were very much only
based about on the head they didn't
openly talk about integration and
embodiment like you've been describing
so
I recognized that I was going through a
spiritual unfolding and I recognize I
have to be humble and keep going as
opposed to thinking that it's done still
I recognize that there's a maturation
process an integration process an
embodiment process that has to follow in
some respects
so I think around this time a few days
later or maybe even the same day I can't
remember but
um
prior to this I was I was eating a vegan
diet
um my intention was to support my
Spiritual Awakening and I thought this
was the best uh the best sort of diet
for that and so when I realized
everything was a dream I said what's the
point of being a vegan like it's all a
dream I I can eat meat
get all this diet stuff
and so I I grabbed uh there's I opened
my fridge you know I had some some pork
chop in there I'd fried it up ate this
pork chop really enjoyed it
in hindsight I can tell eating the meat
was very grounding for me it brought me
a little bit more into my body this this
awakened Consciousness began to settle a
little bit deeper in my body just
remaining that pork chop it made a big
difference especially because leading up
to that I hadn't touched me in a while
so energetically meat is very grounding
food it's not for everybody some people
it's best that they avoid it but for
some I think myself included it's it's
necessary to keep me uh you know in the
world in my body so that was one thing
that I feel like I was inspired to eat
meat I didn't think I'll eat meat to
ground myself I just said you know for
it's all a dream who cares so I ate the
meat then I mean I'm still out of my
body
but uh I thought okay you know this if
this is my life now you know being out
of my body
I gotta learn how to operate in this
state because you know it if an
Awakening took place I gotta figure out
how to navigate and go through you know
learn this new way of functioning with
the flow
um and whatnot and so I thought I saw I
said you know why don't I go to one of
those yoga classes
just see what it's like to move
being out of my body let's see what it's
like to just kind of experience this it
was kind of like I had a it's like I was
playing a video game I got a controller
and my body was like a third person
character out there so it's kind of like
that so I said okay you know maybe yoga
is where I should go just see what
happens so I went to a yoga class
and um you know the teachers saying you
know bring your attention to your breath
in the belly feel your feet on the
ground slowly move your arms upward bend
over et cetera Etc
so after the class I found myself
feeling a little bit more in my body
So eventually I began to understand that
if I bring attention to my body
I can come into my body
and over the next few years I
just began to kind of work on this a
little bit uh not very intensely it was
almost like an organic unfolding but I
recognized that the more I brought
attention to my body the more I settled
into my body and yet I didn't lose this
idea of everything being interconnected
I didn't lose the sense of not being
able to find a sense of Brent in my mind
I still couldn't but I recognized the
more I come into my body
I still have to call myself Brent and
function in the world as an individual
even though I had this massive
experience prior that showed me that
it's all won
my job isn't to like go sit under a tree
and just say everything is one I you
know especially because I'm young I
recognize I have so much life ahead of
me I gotta you know establish myself in
the world
um and then from there
I recognized
I
um I began to feel these emotions in my
heart again I was very numb
but eventually I start to feel things in
my heart and they weren't necessarily
Pleasant I started to feel
anger at times flowing through me in a
like really intense ways like never
before
and and it was like visceral and I felt
alive like like never before
um and and so my relationship with my
emotions began to change
um and I went through having to
understand that emotions aren't a
problem
just because you've had a spiritual
awakening or some sort of spiritual
experience doesn't mean you're not a
human being that's not able to get angry
or upset or triggered or jealous or any
of these things and so I began to
explore ideas of re
Reinventing my relationship with my own
emotional experience
and I gave myself permission to feel
those things and from there
there was a deep deep
sadness and Melancholy in my heart and
the sadness was
a deep desire for God to be in my heart
this is the only way that I can describe
it
a deep desire for God to be in my heart
I felt you know I had known God the
Divine spiritual nature of reality
I've known this on my mind in a cerebral
way this philosophical way and it quite
literally did blast my mind open
but I'm not feeling it not feeling it in
my body in my heart
and so I began to feel this like deep
longing and sadness and Melancholy that
was somewhat
Pleasant I don't know if you're familiar
with what I mean when I say there's
something a little Pleasant about
Melancholy yeah longing is a perfect
word that you use because there is like
a like I've experienced this before I
know that it's true but I just don't
feel it right now you know something
like that yeah something about the pace
of it it's slow it's
it's poetic or something like that but
it felt warm
and I just decided to sit with this and
just be with it and so my meditation
practice re-emerged and it went from
being this like very psychological or
intellectual or mind-based meditation of
just witnessing thoughts so just feeling
this intense love and longing in my
heart
and from there I would meditate lying
down I would just feel this and I would
feel my spine kind of becoming
um
spontaneously moving again like how it
did when I initially was meditating that
very first time the spine would kind of
flow and it wasn't
for some reason I didn't get afraid of
it this time I just let it happen it
just felt like I should just let it
happen it was kind of just this gentle
spinal bending this wasn't yet the major
Rising experience but I could tell that
now my Awakening was moving into my body
and it was within the context of
relationships
that helped me to integrate as well
excuse me so you're asking about how I
had spent you know
but what I'd done to integrate in a body
well I used relationships as a context
and so I thought
it doesn't matter how awakened I am it
doesn't matter if I've seen you know
beyond my ego or whatever you know
Airy fairy ideas I have I mean how
deeply can I relate with somebody can I
attract a partner and keep that partner
and have a meaningful and deep
relationship
and I if I could be honest that was
challenging
um you know I would maybe
have it wasn't even just real in a
romantic sense but you know I'd have
challenges with with my family with with
my parents with uh my friends emotional
things were coming up and I recognized I
got work to do like it doesn't matter
what happened to me in 2012 my mind
being blasted open
you know I'm dysfunctional in my
relationships
um you know
relationships are hard I I just mean I'm
dysfunctional and I don't like this I
feel like I could do better
that's basically where I was coming I
um for myself and for the other people
and so I found relationship was bringing
up a lot of
contact uh emotional contacts for me to
work through and process and contemplate
uh things like insecurity sadness
um you know anxiety jealousy
um attachment aversion
um judgments all of these things were
coming up emotionally and this
processing it's helped me to come into
my body as well because the way I
understood it is that emotions are felt
in the body so when we talk about
embodying our spiritual awakening
experiences it happens in the body and
that it very much has to do with our
relationship with emotions and so
this didn't mean that I was
trying to get to a point where I never
experienced negative emotions no I just
wanted to get to a point where I would
stop judging myself or having them using
spiritual ideas like
spirituality means always being peaceful
so those ideas began to uh um be
challenged eventually I gave myself
permission to feel more and more
and I considered this to be the practice
of self-love unconditional self-love so
it was like
I was loving myself as if I was my own
child coming to me and crying and saying
hey you know this happened to me I feel
sad and I said that's okay it's okay
that you feel this way I'm not here to
tell you don't feel that way I'm not
here to talk myself out of feeling those
ways with spiritual philosophy
feel it fully you have full permission
and this was my Approach of self-love
and from their negative thoughts were
arising
thoughts that seem to contradict all of
my Spiritual Awakening up until that
point
I'm a victim I hate the world's the
world hates me I'm separate blah blah
and I thought it's okay for you to think
that way it's okay I'm not here to talk
myself out of these thoughts based in
separation or based in the illusion of
the ego or false beliefs or whatever no
how do these thoughts you're welcome
here and so I established a safe
container for myself in my practice
where I would just lay down hands in my
heart and feel think anything that would
arise and during those periods I would
overcome a lot of challenges and my
spine would kind of move here and there
but still this wasn't even the major uh
nature Rising experience so we can get
to that in a bit but I'm curious if
anything's come up for you based on what
I shared I know I shared a whole lot no
no I love it I thank you so much I I
want to let you keep ripping because I
feel like you're making so many
wonderful points this um I think this is
a huge important part for anybody who's
listening if they're going through any
sort of similar experiences this is is
it the allowing period you know you
really like took time to allow those
things so we can live so much in the
head so much in the crown and the third
eye chakra that
um you know integrating like the the
real feel feelings of of being in a body
jealousy in in anger and uh you know
resentment and and uh just all these
things that are so human to feel and a
lot of the times our quarrel becomes not
allowing them our Coral becomes
um uh uh like making ourselves feel so
guilty and shameful for even having
these feelings and you're like well I
thought that I was like this enlightened
dude now you know like I shouldn't be
feeling anger and you know here you are
nonetheless and and uh yeah I think um
what is a huge part that took me a while
to uh it helped me give Grace to myself
was
man if if I like there was a time in my
life where I was feeling all these
things and I wasn't aware of them I was
just acting through them and like whoa I
must I must actually if I give myself
the grace of realizing that now that I'm
aware of all these things now I can I
can allow them to be and I can make a
different choice you know meditation
gives you that little that little Gap to
think something but act in a different
way so okay cool now that I'm aware of
all these things I can realize they
don't Define me they're not who I am but
I also don't have to act on those things
you know so maybe in in relationship in
a romantic relationship okay here's
here's jealousy rather than like just
saying that thing you know rather than
just expressing the jealousy and you
know getting caught up in the same
karmic Loop being able to to see the
jealousy happen in my body be able to
see the anger going on being able to
feel the anger in the you know
resentment or whatever it is arising
from my heart it's like okay well all
right that's what that feels like in the
body this is part of the experience you
know and you can kind of tap in it seems
like to the to the crown chakra to the
third eye chakra of realizing the truth
of the thing and then connecting with
like the acceptance you know the
acceptance of it it's okay that this is
here it's it's all right just just let
it be and there is almost this like
unclenching of the Fist when you allow
something you know the um one of the
four noble truths in Buddhism is is
acceptance right so
it's it becomes this profound thing of
allowing yourself to be so human
allowing yourself to consume the meat
you know allowing yourself to these
other energy centers in our body
um you know they deserve just as much uh
um they deserve to be here just as much
as is the higher chakras right so
um yeah okay so man that's so great I
feel like uh there's so many
similarities uh in my journey with with
what you're expressing and um it just
excites me because I think that there's
probably people who are listening who
um you know might feel heard heard and
seen in the same way okay so I would
love to hear about the the
um the release of that you had of this
so like what was your step after this so
you're becoming aware
um you're allowing these things
um you're not it doesn't seem like
you're suffering as deeply in in this
moment um correct me if I'm wrong but it
seems like you feel like you're making
some progress you're integrating the the
spiritual version of yourself as well as
the grounded um just just human
experience that you have going on you're
not rejecting one or the other that's a
huge thing I think for many years I was
like I've got to be spiritual I've got
to be the meditator I've got to be the
like I I can't have lust I can't uh
given and give in to my you know like
just making myself feel shameful for
eating Doritos or something nothing you
know like just this this allowing this
integration of the the above and the
below it seems like this is kind of
where you're at in your journey here
that you're explaining so uh what was
this next step what was this explosion
of energy for you Brent
yeah so this laid this phase that I just
described laid the foundation
upon which
I was being prepared to go through now a
real uh
even more deeper
and Powerful Awakening and integration
period so around this time like I've
said you know my spine is kind of moving
I'm not looking into it much I'm just
letting it happen
for whatever reason I I don't uh make
much of it I'm just loving myself
hands in my heart feel think doesn't
matter it's all welcome here
and around this time I began to connect
online with
uh some spiritual teachers that you know
had YouTube videos and whatnot and and
they were talking about
what we would call Shakti
um also known as Kundalini Shakti which
was this energetic components of
Awakened consciousness
and they were talking about it and
I was also listening to some teachers
that uh had Kundalini Awakenings but
didn't talk about the Awakenings
themselves the Kundalini experience but
instead they talked about being a human
being and being willing to experience
the thoughts the emotions and go through
the different stages of Life Etc and I
can name those teachers I was I was
listening to uh RAM Das who I know
you're familiar with yeah
very much and um Matt Khan
and so they're they're teachers that
have a very heart-centered approach
um you know like you were speaking you
know earlier you know you may have uh
used spirituality against yourself you
know I can't eat the Doritos that's not
spiritual or whatever it is but these
guys you know they never seem to imply
that we should use spirituality against
ourselves come as you are to the path
and it's okay it's it's welcome in fact
the path is welcoming and accepting
yourself as you are with your thoughts
feelings and emotions and so I was
hanging out with these teachers that
were talking about these things and
there was a couple others
um one of them I like his name is David
Sparrow uh he was talking about
Kundalini I'll be honest I didn't even
know what the hell this guy was talking
about I would just listen to the videos
and just kind of go into a sort of
meditative state
now just listen I don't even know what
he's talking I don't know Kundalini I
don't know what he's talking about it's
listening for some reason I was just
drawing these videos and I'm just
listening and I would listen to Matt
Khan and he would talk a lot about like
I was saying using relationships to
contacts for our Awakening I'm not
feeling like we're a victim
um ramdas of course would talk so much
about you know being in the heart and
loving God and and tell their human
stories and he was so vulnerable as well
as well at times about some of his own
shortcomings as a teacher
and so I was hanging out in the vicinity
of these teachers I would say that
looking back I was hanging out in their
energy Fields even it was transmitting
and radiating through video through
audio it doesn't matter it's it's
transcends uh the limitations of the
physical
and in their fields
was this Radiance of Shakti it was this
Radiance of Kundalini and
like I said I didn't know about any of
that so
I'm just enjoying their teachings living
them outs
I eventually
um
connect with uh
I began dating a girl and um
the relationship was was very
mystical and wrapped up in a lot of
synchronicity these these odd
coincidences and Serendipity and you
know
um
just just a lot of interesting stuff
that seem to imply that I had found my
way into the spiritual
perfect relationship you know the
spiritual
you know like a peak of all
relationships is what I felt like
um soul mates whatever you want to call
that's what it felt like it felt like
the Dao had brought me here the flow the
universe had brought us both together we
seem to both know it and recognize it
there's a lot of synchronicity that
seemed just undeniable
um and it all just made sense and when I
say synchronicity I don't mean you know
just texting each other at 11 11. I mean
like
just layers and layers of deep meaning
like some sort of Blockbuster movie and
when we were together this this energy
in my body would become activated and I
felt energetic phenomena
and
I just kind of let it happen it kind of
just felt like well this is what of
course I'm with I'm with my soul mate of
course the energy in my body and my
talkers are going to do all this opening
and of course I'm gonna have these
things and I I it was just very mystery
and magical and and
um the relationship event went really
it's really deep very very quickly and I
was on the top of the world finally I
love myself with self-love to the point
where I was able to attract this partner
and of course they say you know if you
want to attract a great partner love
yourself first overcome your uh you know
your neediness find confidence Etc love
yourself if you want somebody else to
love you I'm like I did it and this is
proof here I am in this relationship you
know I made it
uh her and I um
decide to explore
um psilocybin
along with another friend as well it was
also you know very much uh in wrapped in
this spiritual uh Journey Of Us Together
and
um
you know it's interesting because I've
done a lot of work on Kundalini
um on my channel and I actually haven't
told the story uh in the detail that I'm
about to tell it so uh it's exciting for
me I was you know waiting for for the
right time
um and so so so together
we uh you know we take a little bit of
these uh psilocybin mushrooms and now if
I can preface here
a lot of people do mushrooms a lot of
people do drugs very few have a
Kundalini Awakening and I'm not saying
this to come across as arrogant I'm
saying it just as a warning for those
who may be listening and saying I'll do
it and I'll have a Kundalini Awakening
yeah I
I a lot a lot of spiritual practice like
I've mentioned has gone in
um I was already in the midst of having
energetic phenomena without the uh the
mushrooms so I just want to clarify that
they're powerful tools useful tools but
um not for everybody okay
um
and so and of course you know there's
all the the health and legal issues ETC
um but um
so
we We Begin this trip and uh you know
I'm the experienced one here
and so I feel
a little bit of uh like I'm the guide
and
we're hanging out
[Music]
um
in uh you know the bedroom there
and I'm in the middle of the bed and
they decide you know we're gonna go grab
a glass of water or something and so
they leave the room
uh and I'm in the middle of the bed
there hands in my heart
just loving myself
saying I love you
over and over with each breath and I
feel simultaneously that I'm being held
and that I'm holding myself it's like
I'm holding someone else and someone
else is holding me but it's still me and
I'm I'm you know I'm really with myself
and I'm really going deep I mean this is
the practice that I was doing even
before like I described No Hands In My
Heart
and I'm just loving this it feels
incredible I'm held by God I'm held by
myself I am God I'm a child I'm nobody
I'm everything it's incredible
and certainly have a thought an anxious
thought oh no
they're they're gone you know they've
been I don't know how long they've been
gone you know I thought time can get a
little weird on those experiences I
don't know how long they've been gone
maybe Something's Happened maybe they're
you know somebody got hurt I need to go
check on them I need to leave this
incredible state that I'm in and go
check on them and I hear a voice that
says hey
whatever's taking care of you right now
Brent just taking care of them too
so just just relax
and so I said all right I could trust
that and so I went deep into this
meditation again you know just saying I
love you
over and over I love you and in the
background I was playing music by Ott
it's like a sort of a psybian side dub
type of artist
[Music]
um
similar to Shpongle if you're familiar
with Shpongle but I like trippy hippie
music so
I'm just really in this this incredible
experience
um in this room here and and uh our
friend she's got us she's an artist
she's got a lot of cool art and I'm in a
pretty uncomfortable place
and you know I'm doing this practice I
love you I'm just feeling it's so fully
my heart is growing and growing
and suddenly
I feel my spine Arch and it was like
this explosion of energy
from the base of my spine up my spinal
column
in
two huge jolts
like that
and it was
orgasmic it was
the orgasmic times a thousand and
I
can only describe it as a freight train
moving at light speed
squeezing itself through the shaft in my
spinal column
all the way up to the top of my head
exploding out of my head and I found
myself in this
vast
spaciousness
and you know it was like this incredible
relief
was here as well
and so uh
I came back out of this experience after
I don't know how long
but here I am in the room
and
you know I
was like oh my God you know whoa
and I recognized whoa I'm alone I I
thought I was quite literally having sex
with my partner and
I look at my my uh you know my my
clothing and I'm completely dry you know
I thought I had had a at a release
I thought what the heck was that like
that was some really intense orgasm that
I had that blasted me up you know out of
my body into the ethers
holy moly
and so then
soon after they they returned back
into the room
and I'm looking at them and I can't tell
Who I Am anymore I'm like did I just
come in the room
who are who are we and they're looking
at me saying like
I don't know who we are like Miu are you
me we're all one we are we all were
experiencing this this Unity type
Consciousness type experience of
open-hearted love but it was I mean I
could look back at it now and say it was
debilitating in the sense that I didn't
know who I was like I could have been
anybody in the room
um which was fascinating it was
incredible
um
but I just want to clarify that because
some may be thinking well that's the way
that we need to that's a state that we
need to get to right so operating the
world no you can't operate in the States
you gotta have a sense of Separation but
in the moment it was this total
dissolution of ego and Oneness and
connection to three of us and
um sorry sorry they were experiencing
this too like they were the ones yeah so
yeah I think that's so fascinating wow
yeah it was it was very very incredible
um I think it has a lot to do with the
Psychedelic experience yeah not that the
the not that the the psychedelics were
like tricking us into experiencing that
I think the psychedelics put our nervous
systems in a state of
being in frequency and vibration in
order to experience that
um it's not just a hallucination I think
it's a real experience that we were
having 100 yeah because I know that
people do experience these things
without the use of psychedelics right
um so so we had this experience and so
you know I'm telling them you know what
just happened to me I'm like you know I
have this huge
orgasmic explosion of my spine and uh
my partner said you know we were laying
on the floor in the room uh in the next
bedroom
looking up at the stucco ceiling and
suddenly there was this massive
explosion of of uh the stucco
and I just knew that it was that it
happened at the same time you know that
I had this explosion
so
from there you know we uh
we we just enjoyed this experience
together and you know eventually you
come down and
the Oneness experience began to fade and
dissolve
it was a little bit more functional but
still there was a ongoing perception
like
feeling not just in knowing but there's
a feeling of you know I'm connected with
everything
and
um
you know we went out uh later that
evening for some reason I felt called uh
to just eat something vegetarian
which was unusual for me but I just
that's just what felt right
um
and and so we continued that that day
with having like a pretty incredible
interconnectedness
um that was waning but uh a deep
intimacy it had formed
but uh the next day you know uh I went
to say bye to this you know my
quote-unquote who I thought was my soul
mate at the time and and uh I can tell
that way as I go to say goodbye to her
there's like this little bit of distance
between us that hadn't perceived before
and I said oh you know you know I don't
know if you've ever experienced that but
it's like this
oh it's like a hit and it's like getting
punched in the chest like oh yeah
there's some distance here oh
what happened
and uh
the next uh a couple weeks that distance
began to grow
and I was experiencing a lot of
emotional unsteadiness
loopiness anxiety uh feeling like yeah
like I was like kind of frantic and
uncontrollable emotions and I I was
mourning the end of this relationship
before it was coming because I somewhat
knew it was coming and
um
I um I I didn't know that this was
Kundalini Awakening up until this point
so I was just I was just tripping out
feeling very emotional ungrounded
anxious vibrating my body was buzzing
you know issues with sleep
and the impending end of this
relationship that I could just
intuitively I just knew
um that's you know something was gonna
you know the shoe was gonna drop or
something you know like uh whatever and
so
um I'm at uh I'm working at this car
dealership
I had uh somehow found myself there and
I was very new to the job but wasn't
treated well I wasn't respected well I
wasn't trained properly and there's
three people in my department two guys
were going on extended trips
and um so they sit me down and they
tried to explain to me a long confusing
process of what I'm supposed to do while
they're away to manage this parse
Department
and I can't handle what they're saying I
I know that you know like um
I'm uh
going through this extreme emotional
instability energetic instability I'm
very ungrounded psychological MMS this
relationship went from being incredible
to now suddenly this distance and
they're telling me you know I'm gonna
take a lot of responsibility on it this
job that I haven't been trained for and
they're both leaving on these trips and
so I'm like I can't handle this like
this is just so much that they're asking
of me Plus in my state of being here and
so uh they say okay are you you got that
you're gonna you're gonna be okay and
I'm just like yeah yeah don't worry man
I got you you know we're good we're good
and uh
so uh I got a text message from from my
girlfriend at the time and she says hey
you know Brent's um
I met up with my ex yesterday
and uh you know we're gonna get back
together and you and I are done
and I have this panic attack at this
moment this huge panic attack
and uh these two guys had left to go for
a smoke break something came over me
find myself grabbing my jacket
involuntarily I look at my feet quite
literally it was like I was Associated
but I looked out of my face my feet are
walking out the door and I remember
thinking
I'm walking off the job interesting I
walk out the door I get on the bus I
head home
and I just sat in my room and continued
to love myself because that's all I knew
it was working in the past I just have
to continue loving myself through all
this ordeal eventually
um I described some of the experience to
a friend and she said hey you know that
sounds like Kundalini Awakening ramdas
spoke about his Kundalini Awakening you
know talks about the energy rising up
his spine and I thought oh my God
I had a Kundalini Awakening
and suddenly I'm like
I was listening to these guys the whole
time you know Ram Das I was listening to
Matt Khan he had a Kundalini Awakening
he doesn't talk about it much I was
listening to David sparrow and he would
talk openly about Kundalini Awakening
and like I said I would just kind of
listen I wouldn't I didn't know what
this guy was talking about so I'm like
oh my God I experienced this what I was
aware of this whole time and it took me
a couple weeks to make sense of this
experience to make to come up with what
I had gone through and suddenly I'm like
oh my God I had a Kundalini Awakening
and that explains why I'm so messed up
and out of my body and
you know excuse me energetically
unstable and
feeling all this electricity and
vibrations in my body and can't sleep
okay
and so I knew
um I did a did a research or something I
said okay I'm going through a
purification period the energy is
bringing up all of the on
uh addressed issues that I've been
carrying in my life much of it maybe I
thought I was over
you know maybe I thought I had maybe I
thought I'd ex I had overcome insecurity
nope I thought I'd overcome grief and
confusion and sadness trauma I thought I
had addressed all of that no and so I I
sat in my room and I continued with the
practice that I was doing before the
Awakening the practice I was doing
during The Awakening which of course
hands in my heart saying I love you to
whatever was arising
and intense things were coming up
um a lot of grief around the Heartbreak
things from the past from childhood
um raw things emotions without a label
without content just raw raw sadness
grief and I could tell that this was
something from the collective
not that I was healing
the world per se it was more like this
is a collective wound that I've
inherited just because I'm a human being
on this Earth
those things were Rising
past life memories were arising
um
all sorts of
difficult things emotional I was crying
vomiting fevers oh the fevers were
intense sweating cold sweats all sorts
of really challenging things but
fortunately I knew what I was going
through
I knew it was Kundalini up until this
point I had developed this relationship
with like I I was saying the word I'm
using lately has been the Dao I had this
relationship with the Dao I knew that I
was supported it had supported me from
day one just by bringing me Eckhart
Tolle's book and I just gave all my
faith to it I said please just like
don't drop me now don't abandon me now
um I'm trusting you like you know like
I'm trusting this is going to work out
it's not happening for no reason
and so
I
moved through this process
six weeks straight I just meditated six
seven hours a day not
um because I was a monk or something I
just I didn't know there was nothing
else for me to do the intention the the
emotions were coming up so intensely I
had no other choice I just had to sit
with it and I would go through a healing
cycle and when I refer to a healing
cycle I mean like uh a phase it could be
a couple days it could be six hours it
could be one night it could be a weekend
whatever where I would be processing
some difficult emotions but when that
phase ended quite literally I felt
healed transformed more peaceful more
spacious more safe in my body and so I
caught on to what was going on here I
caught on I said every time there's a
cycle of something coming up I go
through it I come out on the other side
transformed and so I developed more and
more faith and confidence in the process
and so I I continued with this process
for uh like I said six weeks for the
most intense then eventually I started
to get a little bit more
gradual and subtle and I felt more
stable
um and eventually I found myself
being able to look back and say wow you
know
I think I'm through the most difficult
parts of that
I think I'm stable I'm steady I'm calm
I'm centered things will still come up
and things can still come up so this
happened to me back in 2015. so about
eight years I think so things can still
come up but up up from that point on I
caught on to the game I understood
um and so there was a willingness to
heal and face what I have without you
know like I said using spiritual bypass
and you're using my spirituality against
myself and so the if I can describe the
energy initially awakened up in my crown
the top of my head then it awakened from
The Roots all the way up to the top of
my head so now the entire body was
awakened you could say and I found
myself abiding
for the most part in my heart
which I'd like to call like the center
because it's the center of the spiritual
awakening it happens up at the top of
the head as well as the emotional and
bodily awakened that happenings happens
from the root and so in the heart I'm
able to like
integrate the two and I like to think
that you know I'm working towards more
and more deeply embodying my
spirituality as a human being in the
world
and so um you know I can pause there and
you can see uh
but it's coming up for you any questions
I know it was intense it was good to
finally talk about it in that way I I
was waiting at the right time oh
beautiful yeah yeah I mean dude thank
you so much for sharing all that like
it's such a you know it's such an
innately personal thing but uh like I
said I mean and I think probably like
your journey as well is when we hear
other people telling about their their
versions of it or like how they went
through it it's like such this feeling
of being heard you're like oh gosh you
know like with you you're like oh wow
that's what's going on a Kundalini
Awakening like I I had one oh geez and
then suddenly you kind of have a mile
marker of sorts like you're like okay so
there is a some sort of apparent
direction in which I'm I'm heading right
you know so okay so I had this now what
you know it's the because it's such a
destabilizing process for for so long
you know and and I think um uh you know
for some of us it
varies I mean I I've heard people talk
about how it could be you know anywhere
from a couple months of an experience to
you know 10 15 years of experiencing
this and you know I don't think there's
a wrong way or a right way or a um set
in stone way but I think that um you
know once it starts to happen once the
Kundalini begins to rise or even like
the
you know it's interesting because like
very much in you're saying this too is
it's there's so many experiences that
lead up to it that are for sure a part
of it you know it's not like your
Kundalini Awakening only starts when it
rises up your spine and you have like
some sort of Awakening experience like
for you on the psychedelics where
um you know you kind of like saw this
white light it was like this orgasmic
feeling through your body like that's as
much the Kundalini Awakening as the the
things that led up to it over over the
course of the few years so you know one
thing that I noticed for me
um
I've always had this fascination with
time like time is always so interesting
to me in so many levels like my
um my first eight years of of being a DJ
and Performing and stuff it went by DJ
Kronos who's the Greek Titan of time
um and and I was just like man if I
could just you know there's those
moments where an artist on stage could
make you just like time just goes by so
fast suddenly you realize it's been 45
minutes but you've just been transcended
and transported in this way you know I
thought I always thought that was
fascinating
um but I think that it's funny because I
didn't even realize my fascination with
time is is like spiritual it's uh
because when these things happen to you
you start to realize the connectiveness
of everything and once you allow
um you know your journey to happen
you're like oh of course so I had to
have those things happen to me when I
was a child or else I wouldn't be this
version or I wouldn't be able to like
you know speak about these versions of
these things that are happening to me
now
um yeah so so the the the understanding
of time itself seems to uh kind of
change when you're on a spiritual
journey and I don't know if it's just
just with Kundalini or Awakenings or
whatnot but um I think a lot of people
can kind of resonate with
seeing how the series of events that led
up to the spiritual awakening and where
we are now are you know it sounds kind
of cheesy but like they're also perfect
you know they're 100 it's like like oh
of course those things had to happen for
me to be this integrated
um you know not you know for lack of a
better term actualized like a you know
some version of my actualized self or
I'm where I'm supposed to be on my path
you know not not an arrival of being you
know an actualized avatar or something
but
um yeah it just kind of gets you to be
right where you're at now
um wow okay so
now that now that you have gone through
these things
um
I think um
I think I think for me there was moments
where uh I was so enthralled and so like
obsessed with I because I had I had a
similar uh where I was like I couldn't
help but meditate like for a long
periods of time I couldn't help but do
yoga like my it's so interesting because
it was such like a kooky weird insane
moment of my life
but it was all I could do like so I
would I'd wake up in the morning um and
luckily for a while I had this like
schedule where um I would have like long
bouts of I would have weeks or months
where I'm not really working or I'm not
really having to do much I'm not really
having to be social so I can kind of be
in these esoteric realms for a long time
where I'm reading a ton of philosophy
I'm listening to audiobooks I'm like
going on long runs listening to you know
Ram Das or any of these spiritual
teachers so I'm I'm in this mindset
um and I feel like I'm I'm not really
having to be grounded in in a sense
which is I don't think I really
recommend in some ways but I think it's
also how what I had to do
um I would walk outside I had this
wonderful backyard of like privacy and
there was nature and birds and there was
like tons of squirrels and like
sometimes I'd be meditating and like a
deer would walk right up to me where not
like touching distance but probably like
within like 15 feet and I would sense
their energy or something and kind of
open my eyes and realize they've just
been staring at me like what what is
going on so I was in um but also at the
same time I would be walking out to
to my meditation spot and I would just
lean over and vomit like I would just
throw up and and like I'm like okay yep
there's my morning bomb and I go sit
down and meditate and like now
retrospect me like me like what was
going on like I was just accepting that
as normal in that moment
um so yeah man I I uh just just uh just
to Ramble On I mean it's so interesting
in these experiences they really are so
far-fetched you know and then some time
comes on and you're able to kind of come
down into grounded reality you know and
uh I've said this before you might have
heard me uh repeat this over and over
from ramdas's uh uh always remember your
your Buddha nature and your Social
Security number you know around us has
said that and I always love it because
that's that's kind of part of what it
was you know I think anybody going
through an Awakening we have these
these moments of being extremely
spiritual or like we can't even fathom
like we can't even hold a conversation
um in kind of the grounded realm of
things you know uh I remember
for me I I went to uh after the pandemic
I work in Live Events and so I wasn't
able to to work and make an income for a
while and so I got to the point where I
was like I need a job like I got to pay
the bill sort of thing and so I was
working at um UPS I was a supervisor
over there and I remember like my first
few weeks I was nervous I was like man I
have been
I've been on Mars for many months and
now I need to like go like I'm sending
people's packages you know it's like a
very grounded thing and I remember um
introducing myself as Jake and they're
like oh Jake from State Farm and they
would say like things like that like
just jokes from the TV and like you know
just our typical and I was like oh no
I've gotta I'm gonna need to run out of
this building I can't handle like the
like and it took me a while then I would
start kind of like
accepting that and joking back with them
and talking about not talking about
spiritual stuff not trying to talk about
God in every moment not trying to teach
everybody about meditation but just
having a silly time at work with the
people I was working with and you know
then slowly I was able to kind of like
see their beauty and I would appreciate
ah man this person like they're not like
me but that's okay like they're like
them and they're pretty awesome you know
and start seeing the beauty in people
and so you know there's just like this
integration process of there's a lot of
fear of thinking that you're gonna like
lose your spiritual knowledge or like
man I think I was up there on the
mountain and I've got to descend down
and
um I think that you've described it in
your way Sprint like a beautiful way of
of of of having both you know in a sense
like there's this uh
um I'm probably not the right term but
as above so below like you you're you're
able to kind of
um the the integration of being
spiritual and being a grounded a human
we're in this body we're in this you
know uh meat suit and and all this
um and um I think
yeah I don't know I think that's an
important part to point out because
there's often points for me
um another experience that happened for
me was
when I first kind of had
um mine didn't shoot out of my head but
I had my mind connected to my heart and
it was this insane experience that like
lasted multiple days of being in this
like it was disassociative but I felt
very stuck in my body
and I remember searching on online I was
just on Reddit even I even posted on a
Reddit Forum I forget which one I'm like
asking for help and I was like I think
that I went too far I think that I
opened my third eye I can't close it I
didn't know what I was talking about I
was literally searching up YouTube
videos how to close your third eye like
because I was just so ungrounded in so
many ways but you know now my
understanding of those sorts of things
like it's not you need to shut down one
or or add more to the other there is
like a Natural Balance and integration
that that um seems to happen
um so yeah um Okay so we've still got
some time left I I do have like so I had
a couple notes for you Brian um and of
course if there's anything else you you
want to mention for sure bring it in but
um I did I was curious so you were
talking about this moment where you had
this experience and you had two people
around you two people who were close and
you kind of had a synchronistic
um like you you felt this this bright
white light you you had this orgasmic
feeling and they also had some
correlation of feeling the same thing
and they walk in the room and you're
like who's like is this my mouth is this
your mouth who are you who am I it is
sort of like I mean oh wow how
fascinating is that like what an
incredibly interesting thing as far as
I'm concerned you know
um have you and what do you think about
the uh have you heard of like Joe
dispenza's Retreats
um have you heard of Joe dispenza so so
he I mean I don't know how exactly to
put it but I think that he's basically
having giant like Convention Center
level Retreats multiple days long where
he's activating people's Kundalini
um and not just him you know I'm sure
these people their life has led them to
these this is like maybe like a
self-help sort of seminar if anybody
who's listening a sort of Tony Robbins
um I think it's it's kind of up there
with that I think Joe dispense is a
little more esoteric and a bit more
intense but Brett what do you think um
based off of your spiritual experience
what you've read what you've gone
through personally what do you think
about this fascinating thing you know
we're having Retreats of people coming
together to
um whether intentionally or not if
that's the word they use but kind of
awaken their Kundalini like I mean what
do you think about that and how much
have you heard about any of that
yeah so Joe dispense is a fascinating
guy
of uh like a lot of admiration for him
I feel like he's
one of the people who are tactful not to
openly discuss Kundalini Awakening
um blatantly maybe in the way that I do
because it turns off a lot of people and
I think that's conducive to why he's
able to attract like you said convention
level Convention Center size audiences
and people from going on Retreats from
around the world because
um a lot of his work centers around
healing in general emotional healing
physical healing even so I would say
that's um I I don't know too much about
his work but I know I I'm gonna Tarboro
a strong guess that he's dealing with
awaken Kundalini himself he had an
interesting uh traumatic experience and
and I've read a little bit of his work
and he does refer to
an energy that seems quite synonymous
with Kundalini I'm sure he's must have
referred to it as Kundalini uh you know
in a clear way at some point or another
as well but um I think that what his
work involves is tapping into that
energy that we all have
to use it for healing transformation but
doesn't necessarily mean that everybody
is going to have their Kundalini
awakened per se I think that we can all
um experience it from time to times uh
in a sort of active State and then it
goes back into sleep into dormancy
um so it's kind of like a stirring of it
or a stimulation of it or tapping into
uh you know the different ways we could
look at it like the life force or the
chi and using that to facilitate some
form of transformation but
um I don't know if he approaches it as
like a directly and obvious like
Kundalini Awakening event but there are
some that do
um there are some that uh you know serve
as like um
at least if they're operating in a sort
of Indian uh tradition they would call
themselves a guru and some offer what's
called shaktipot which is a transmission
of Shakti which is synonymous with
Kundalini it's this transmission of the
spiritual power from the guru to the
aspirant and this can serve to awaken
another's Kundalini so in the same way
that uh
my friends and I
had that shared sort of experience
it's because like this our energy is
contagious you know even if you're sad
right it's it's it's radiating outwards
and we can pick up on it and so if
you're in a high
state of consciousness
others can also pick up on it and if
they're receptive and open
they can begin to vibrate with you the
nervous system can begin to become
co-regulated with you and they can
experience their own energetic shifts
within their own nervous system within
their own chakras and for some that can
lead to a full-blown Kundalini Awakening
for others it can be a temporary
state of expanded Consciousness that
then they return back to an ordinary
State later on
um it varies greatly across the board it
all depends on uh what a person brings
to the table in terms of you know the
type of work they've done in the past uh
their openness their receptiveness the
themes that they're exploring in their
life what their uh you know their
mission is in life as well not
everybody's meant to have a Kundalini
Awakening and become a Kundalini
podcaster or something right but some
are meant to have an experience
connection between mind and heart maybe
like what you describe or maybe they're
meant to have an expanded State of
Consciousness in their mind and they
kind of tap into incredible creativity
and that's how they bring forth their
gifts everyone has sort of different
things
um but there are some events like that I
would also just say as a preface not a
preface a disclaimer you know some
people offer these
shaktipot Transmissions or they may are
they might advertise that they're going
to awaken your Kundalini and they may
genuinely have some
spiritual
um skills but that doesn't mean that
uh you know in a weekend you're going to
become enlightened it doesn't mean that
those people are also Beyond taking
advantage of you because some people
with great Spiritual Development
um still have unaddressed wounds and
tendencies and it can lead to uh toxic
Dynamics
um you know you can quite literally call
it you know I can lead to abusive Cults
you could say so it's important that
everyone uses their discernments
um but that doesn't mean we avoid those
places you know like I said I was
enjoying the transmission
from guys like Ram Das David Sparrow
Matt Khan Through YouTube through
YouTube so uh like I said you know the
energy is contagious and it's not
limited to the the material world it can
be transmitted through a text message
even
yeah absolutely yeah I think that's a
very fascinating thing to point out too
is is uh I mean it's really kind of you
know in in the uh you know Eastern
philosophy there's we'll hear about um
Saints where people will you know line
up to meet these people we have a AMA
the hugging Saint if you if you've heard
of her
um I've heard from experiences of people
you know like not really believing in
that sort of thing but then they go
there and they're in her vicinity and
they're just like it's undeniable like
there's just this thing where you just
love this woman like you're just you
just feel intense love when you're
around this and uh yeah for anybody
listening you could pretty much this is
a saint uh she's still alive today
actually
um and she she's called the hugging
scene because she just lines up for
countless countless hours I mean I think
it's they have like I feel like I've
heard people mention that she does
multiple days or like at least a day
straight where she doesn't like Sydney
she doesn't get up and use the restroom
or anything she just yeah one person
after the next gets to hug her and they
feel as intense Bliss and it's she's
present with every single person and she
will be you know like matching their
energy and and um yeah so so it's so
it's interesting uh that we have these
beings
um and where all these beings too is is
what's actually very interesting
um that
we almost have like um have an influence
on other people's energy you know we
have
um
there's like a permission to see some
form of Truth
with some versions of the spiritual path
um and I think uh yeah I guess when I
brought up the um Joe dispenza thing
um
because yeah whether they use a language
or not that kind of seems like what
they're doing like I again before I
really knew much about Kundalini or
anything about Kundalini I was doing
some uh just like guided meditations
from Joe dispenza
um and you know you're you're kind of
intentionally like squeezing those
different areas of your body and you're
kind of like imagining things going up
through your head so I think that I
don't think that he's trying to like
cause massive Kundalini Awakenings but
he certainly is you know it's it's the
through the realm of healing you know
but but I will say you know it's that's
why I'm so I'm grateful for your work
I'm grateful for people like you who are
um you know you're just you're peppering
your YouTube channel with just such
perfect tools to use along the way you
know so like maybe people who have
listened to your channel
um are coming to you from Reading Joe
dispenza's work or not um you know not
even just him just these various
teachers who are
um you know I Expediting the spiritual
process along the way and you come out
the other side and you're like dude what
is happening because in the Western
World we don't have a lot of this
language like we said in the beginning
is hidden behind religious and spiritual
texts and a lot of our modern ways of
speaking about these things it's very
like whoa keep keep that woo-woo stuff
away from me or keep that religious
stuff away from me but there's there's a
lot of wonderful stuff in it you know
and so
um me as someone growing up
I think I would be you know like a
self-diagnosed agnostic or some sort of
like atheist Without Really Ever
thinking deeply about it I just like to
call myself that
um uh you know and I started going
through all these experiences myself and
um I think maybe maybe I could have
helped myself more along the way if I um
if I had a you know childhood and
upbringing in teenage years where where
I read these sorts of of books that I
find fascinating and wonderful now
there's just a lot of good juicy real
human
energetic slash being uh grounded human
being
it meshes very well in in that realm
um right
yeah so um we I don't know did you have
any more thoughts on that Brent did you
have any more um yeah well I wanted to
just thank you for uh
for checking out my work in general I
appreciate the support the reason that I
do that work is for exactly that reason
uh the reason I talk about Kundalini
openly
um is because
when I understood that I was going
through Kundalini Awakening that was the
greatest gift that could have gotten on
this path
um in a sense and so I just want to give
that to other people because like you
said I I'm I'm I just want to validate
what you said many people are going
through different meditations on YouTube
or some sort of breath work or some sort
of psychedelic experience even
facilitated by a so-called professional
or a shaman or somebody that's you know
offering these things as a service and
they're having genuine Kundalini risings
and Awakenings and the facilitator or
the teacher or the YouTube guide or the
app
has no resources for them there's no
support
um
they have to go out and figure this out
on their own
um now we could argue that yeah that's
part of the journey it's part of how the
Dow wants to unfold and I can make you
know we can make a strong argument for
that for sure but I think that we do
still have the responsibility that if we
are playing the role of some sort of
energy healer or Reiki master
et cetera Etc meditation teacher yoga
teacher if we're you know facilitating
breath work or psychedelic workshops you
need to understand that very significant
powerful energetic unfoldings like Queen
Elaine Awakening can take place and they
can turn the person's life upside down
and I feel that
it's important that not everybody has to
go through kundalin Awakening you don't
need to be a go through Kundalini awake
in order to teach meditation but just
become aware of these things become
aware of some resources
just so that if somebody approaches you
and says hey in that meditation I had a
huge explosion of energy from my spine
in my head in my heart I can't stop
vibrating after that meditation what's
going on and somebody can say like how
my friend said to me that sounds like
Kundalini just hearing the word
then they can go off and Google and
they'll be okay it's just I just think
that's so important because I've come
across like many yoga teachers who
who don't know what this stuff is they
don't know that yoga has a very strong
energetic component to it I just think
it's about stretching and being you know
finding a little bit of peace or
something that's a component to it but
the energetic potential of these
practices is massive and
um that's why I'm doing this work and I
encourage anybody out there just to
if you had an experience like yourself
um you know your podcast is incredible
you've got so many different topics that
you're talking about from so many
different perspectives and people coming
out from different uh walks of life but
you still mentioned Kundalini here and
there in your process and your Awakening
and how you're going through this that
alone these little hints just get the
conversation going it's out in the
Zeitgeist of our conversation
collectively it's a known thing now
right so somebody listening to your
podcast that's interested in maybe the
you know your experiences with uh mental
health they may hear something that
you're talking about Awakening they may
say whoa whoa whoa what's this guy
talking about it's kind of happened to
me finally I have a words describe what
I've experienced so the more we get it
out there here and there the more people
have a little bit of breadcrumbs to pick
up it's like you know if I can just like
belabor this thing it's like you know
putting a little bit of like Flags in a
forest that Mark the way out if somebody
gets lost they see a flag like okay I
can find my way now it's like that so
that's my intention with this work
because you know
it's powerful profound transformative
stuff and we need to raise awareness we
need to raise awareness I think that's
where the collective is going because
more people are going to be going
through these shifts more and more
people
um I just wanted to just uh comment
briefly on Amma I think uh she's
incredible I actually uh
attended one of her meetings in Toronto
and yeah a huge crowd
um now did you experience lineup did you
did you hug her or did you experience
like the energy like I was mentioning
yeah yeah so I mean even just being
within the vicinity of that place there
is a palpable uh field energetic field
that she is you know radiating
um I think it goes in conjunction with
the people that are attracted to her as
well we're all collectively rating a
very uh High vibratory energetic field
you could say and uh yeah so I went uh
up for a hug I had gone with my with my
girl girl my current girlfriend
um a few years ago and
she'll hug individuals and she also will
hug couples together and so I went up
with my girlfriend and the host uh you
know one of her her helpers there uh
ushered me to get a hug and so I hugged
Emma by myself and you know you you it's
very possible you can feel like this
great piece it's like you're really
being held by by like the Divine mother
or something to that to that nature at
least that's what I felt I feel like
everyone might have their own experience
and then the uh help or recognize it oh
this woman is his partner all right send
her up give them both the hug together
so I got a two hugs out of it so I got
to hug uh partner with my with my
girlfriend as well so it was a special
experience for sure it was uh it was
exciting and and she you know gives a a
talk
um
uh so sort of a thought song to the big
group
um and she just on the topic of
integration and embodimenting being a
human being
you know she's the hugging Saint
incredible you know she could quite
literally sit and just hug people all
day or even just not say anything and
just be in silence but she's uh a
humanitarian
um you know she's helped a lot of poor
people I think she's done a lot I mean
the the the the philanthropy that has
come out through her organization is
it's unprecedented and so it's just
another example of what it means to be
human and yeah she may be enlightened
herself realized or whatever you want to
call it but she's still you know got her
feet on the ground helping people to
to you know have a bit of a better life
and I think that's really important as
well it's important message for sure
yeah yeah I mean yeah it's it's a it's
just a great example of where uh service
seems to reign supreme you know that you
hear that in all these sort of just all
the religious and spiritual teachings
they they'll have some sort of like
serve people and you'll see you know and
it is that I think finding your own
version of service there is some uh like
freedom and it's um you know Terence
McKenna says uh uh um
what is it like you you jump off the
cliff
into the abyss and realize it's a
feathery bed or something like that you
know it's the as you walk upon the path
the path will appear you know it's those
sorts of things and I think service is
uh you know we have our own version of
service and it just feels right to us
like not trying to mimic the way that
somebody else does it but just being you
know I mean I'm an artist and so I I
it's a constant
um you know my work is to figure out
what's what's me like what's my art what
what it what what am I expressing you
know and oh am I trying to mimic
somebody am I taking them as inspiration
or am I you know really really giving
what I only I can give and um that's
kind of the rule of the artist but I
think it's also the role of a spiritual
teacher in a sense too you know I think
I feel like I see spiritual teachers as
artists themselves you know you know
learning about their own paintbrush and
learning um you know ways in which they
can uh paint reality for for other
people um to make us all feel more more
grounded while also feeling connected to
the divine you know
um I I would like to to round about so I
have this uh one of the books that I
bought was I don't know if you can see
it nice oh yeah backwards yeah I don't
know if you've read that one um but uh
it's Kundalini video the science of
spiritual transformation uh it's from
Joanne uh Shiva parita hair again I
don't know why I just butchered that so
bad
um but so so I read about that um I got
that book and I feel like it helped me
in in some senses
um I will also recommend for anybody
else going through Kundalini um there
there's a podcast called Buddha at the
gas pump I mentioned that to the to you
the other day um you said you've checked
it out there's actually a whole category
on the back Gap Buddha at the gas pump
website of Kundalini and it's a just
this wonderful man Rick Archer uh who
talks with uh spiritually Awakening
beings and uh there's just like a lot of
good resources in there and again you're
hearing people talk about their
Kundalini Journey so it's there's really
something very grounding about feeling
heard and seen and like oh wow I'm going
through these same things and like it's
okay for me to allow them because other
people have gone through them and
they've in their you know reassuring me
that that that's going well
um I will also mention Aaron apke has
some good stuff on YouTube about
Kundalini Awakenings I just wonder if
you had um of course your channel like
your channel is so great for anybody
going through Spiritual Awakening I feel
like your thumbnail those are great for
it your titles are great really you draw
people right in where they're gonna need
to go so like man keep doing what you're
doing thank you so much for your work
but um do you have anybody else that you
might kind of throw in throw into the
pile for anybody who maybe they've
listened up to this point and they're
like wow I think I have gone through
this or I am going through this or I
know a friend who's going through this
what else might you throw their way what
other you know books or resources
um I I recently read a book by an
incredible woman named Dr Yvonne Cason
it's called touched by the lights I
found that to be a really clear
documenting some of the after effects
the physical After Effects the energetic
After Effects psychic after effects of
the Awakening process
um she's incredible she's been through
her own uh really significant ships
there's a book called the spiritual
awakening guide by Mary Weller chutan
which I really enjoy as well
uh
uh especially after
the major shifts uh on the Mind level
like how I described earlier on in my
journey that massive Awakening in my
mind seeing you know non-duality or the
shift out of ego and no self I found the
work by Adia Shanti to be very very uh
useful for me so he has a book called
The End Of Your World
uncensored Straight Talk on the nature
of Enlightenment and so he speaks about
integration and embodiment uh in that
book and and uh really clear ways he is
another teacher that doesn't openly talk
about Kundalini before from what I
understand he he's been through
Kundalini Awakening it's not uh within
the wording that he uses often
um but it's there and you know there's
many teachers that have gone through
that don't don't talk about it openly
um because of course it's it's
polarizing uh and scary for some I can
turn some people
um let me see here
um I love um
of course uh The Power of Now
uh the work by Matt Khan has been very
incredible for me to uh
to lay the foundation for what it means
to Unconditionally Love I found Matt
Collins work uh to really be incredible
and uh for a bit of a uh
I guess I could say light enjoyable read
ROM Das would be here now oh yeah uh a
plus yeah incredible incredible yeah
yeah I I love how you mentioned um you
know not a lot of these people really
they don't use the same terminologies
they're not always talking about
Kundalini Awakening but I think once you
kind of have a grasp of what it is
um you you can hear a lot of these
spiritual uh you know conversations are
kind of talking about Kundalini waking
I've heard um I don't think it was you
I've heard somebody talking about how uh
you know a very like if you imagine in
your mind a very
um Christian uh like older lady uh who
you know maybe her her hobby is knitting
uh and maybe I'm maybe I'm playing this
from around talk actually but uh like
she she has she may have gone through a
very profound Kundalini Awakening but
she would never use those terminologies
she would use um you know christ-like
Consciousness or you know probably
wouldn't even say that but um she she
would
there's many different
ways of describing this experience you
know I think Kundalini in a lot of ways
is just another way it's another way
that we can gain information in some
grounding and you know I think if you're
listening and and this sounds like you
know enticing to you maybe that's your
your path of learning what's going on in
your experiences maybe you pursue a
little bit farther down Kundalini
Awakening um whether you typically use
those terminologies or not um just to
say that many different people are going
through what we would probably consider
Kundalini Awakening if it's something
that we all had a
um you know the a similar language for
so yeah
um well said yeah uh so man I think
we're getting up here in time I would
love to wrap it up I would love uh uh of
course please mention where to find you
I will link things um in the description
of course but I would love one more
thing just whatever pops into your mind
for anybody listening who is going
through a Kundalini awaken or has going
through a Kundalini Awakening or they're
just on the spiritual path uh do you
have a message for them do you have
anything that comes to mind like what
um speak to these people who are on the
Awakening path anything pop into your
mind Brett
yeah I feel like saying you know one
step at a time
when things are difficult
just be with that one step that one
difficult step
when things are going great you can also
recognize that you are
you're walking you're moving even the
great things may change as you continue
forward so you enjoy those things but be
mindful as well that's uh nothing lasts
good or bad one step at a time be fully
present with whatever's whatever's there
the difficult things
the exciting things the mystical things
I like to think of it as uh as a Journey
part of my aim is to really squash the
idea that there's ever a Finish Line no
Finish Line not in my view we keep going
and and uh exploring new things and and
revisiting things in new ways and and no
matter what you're going through
it's all welcome unconditionally
unconditionally
the real
deal spiritual path with an open heart
does not push anything away
nothing at all it's all welcome here
yeah
so beautifully said so beautifully said
yeah uh
yeah allow it allow it that's absolutely
beautiful
um all right man uh real quick drop
where to find you out you're under Brent
sphere on on Instagram and YouTube and
everything yeah
yeah Brent Spirit yeah and uh you can
also find me on my website
brentspirit.com uh I've got my podcast
on uh Spotify and apple it's called the
spiritual awakening show
excellent cool definitely check that out
um Brent thank you so much for your time
again I will link all those sorts of
things and um man certainly stay in
touch I really love talking to you man
and I really love uh just consuming your
work and um I I love you know as I'm
scrolling through on on Instagram and
stuff just seeing seeing your Clips so
please keep doing what you're doing and
thank you so much for doing it oh thank
you you're so so welcome and right back
at you man keep doing what you're doing
I've been uh listening to some of your
music spoken word cool stuff man I
really had a great time today so thank
you thank you so much
cool excellent man we'll be in touch
I'll let you know I'll tag you in clips
and whatnot as as I make them and then
once I drop the episode I'll shoot you a
message okay
sweet all right take care now love
yourself everybody peace out much love
peace hello and welcome to the junkyard
love podcast
[Music]
at what age do we learn how to have
better conversations
at what age should we learn to have
better conversations with ourselves
no
no no no no no
[Music]
knowledge is power
reality is
[Music]
thank you